Finding Aid for Shirley P. Wolfe papers, 1960s-2001
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Shirley P. Wolfe papers 1951-2001
Wolfe, Shirley P.
0.9 linear feet
2010032 Aa 2
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of Shirley P. Wolfe (donor no. 10296 ) and came to the library in 2009. Additional material acquired by the Bentley Historical Library in December 2012.
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Shirley P. Wolfe, a resident of Ann Arbor, Michigan, was a member of various adoption and civil organizations.
The Shirley Wolfe collection documents her interest in a number of social, political, and environmental issues, namely adoptions, conservation and environmental education, human rights and civil liberties, peace and disarmament, housing, and community development.
The Adoptions and adoption organizations series is arranged alphabetically by subject or name of organization, the files include newsletters from various organization, clippings, brochures, and various mailings. Some of the organizations represented in the papers include the Council on Adoptable Children and the North American Council on Adoptable Children.
The Social Issues series contains 1950s-early 1960s material on Ann Arbor community, environmental conservation education, and peace and nuclear disarmament. Ann Arbor community related material includes letters identifying Shirley Wolfe and her husband Arthur as the Ann Arbor community self-survey representatives; 1952 newsletters on the subject of Interntional communities (mostly published outside of the state of Michigan); and material related to equal housing in Ann Arbor. Material on peace and nuclear disarmament contains newsletters and bulletins of various organizations, including women's, on the subject of radiation pollution, politics, and war, among other issues.
Subjects:
Adoption--Government policy.; Adoption--Michigan.; Adoption--United States.; Council on Adoptable Children.; Intercountry adoption.; Interracial adoption.; North American Council on Adoptable Children.; Peace--Societies--Periodicals; Peace movements--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Women pacifists--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; University of Michigan. School of Natural Resources.
- Adoption and adoption organizations
  - Adopting, General, 1960s (Box 1)
  - Adoption Clippings & Information, 1960s (Box 1)
  - Colombian American Friends, 1975-1986 (Box 1)
  - Council on Adoptable Children & Ann Arbor OURS, 1967-1986 (Box 1)
  - Foster Care, 1975-1990 (Box 1)
  - Friends for all Children, 1974-1990 (Box 1)
  - Friends of Children, Inc., 1984-2001 (Box 1)
  - Friends for International Adoption and Assistance, (later became affiliate of OURS), 1975-1986 (Box 1)
  - International Adoption, General, 1984-1999 (Box 1)
  - Inter-racial Adoption, The Children's Voice, General Adoption, clippings, etc., 1972-1992 (Box 1)
  - Michigan Families for Children and Michigan Families of Adopted Foreign Children, 1977-1981 (Box 1)
  - North American Council on Adoptable Children, 1968-1989 (Box 1)
- Social issues
  - Community (Box 1)
    - Ann Arbor coomunity self-survey, 1956 (Box 1)
    - Equal housing, 1962and undated (Box 1)
    - Intentional communities, 1952-1956 (Box 1)
  - Environmental conservation education,1951-1956,scattered years (Box 1)
  - Peace and nuclear disarmament,1959-1962,1970 (Box 1)